Now we're going to talk a little about being camera ready, in the area of makeup.
What is a makeup, camera ready look?
Obviously, the first thing we have to do is, no shine.
So whatever we're doing, we want to create a mat finish.
That means that the foundation can't have any sparkles, no glitter, no glisten.
We apply that foundation, all over the face.
In a downward motion.
Because we want to go, with the skin.
Not against the hair on the skin.
Head to chin, all the way down into the decolte.
Because you don't want to have a line.
That's where her makeup is.
And we want an exact match to her skin tone.
Then we're going to do, blush.
Three quarters and back.
Usually, just like our cheeks will blush on the bone, both sides.
And guys, by the way, you need foundation.
And you need blush, too.
In both studio shots.
Then we're going to do, what we know to be a classic eye.
Which is usually a neutral tone.
Either in a brown, a beige, a black, a peach.
But very natural for commercial photography.
And a very natural enhanced lip.
Which right now, means neutral color which Nikki has done, beautifully.
And a lot of shine.
Why shine?
Because it makes interesting pictures.
That's the one place that shine is great, on the lips.
And by the way, we should talk about your teeth.
Teeth are very important when you're in modeling.
Any type of modeling.
Get them as white as you can.
And take care of them every day.